Register of the Fred Lyman Adair Papers, 1918-1942
Hoover Institution Archives
Fred Lyman Adair Papers,
1918-1942
50009
Adair, Fred Lyman, 1877-
8 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 3 envelopes, 2 phonorecords (5.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, reports, notes, printed matter, and photographs, relating primarily to activities of the American Red Cross in Belgium, 1918-1919, and to the America First Committee, 1940-1942.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1950.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
America First Committee; American National Red Cross; World War, 1914-1918; World War, 1914-1918--Belgium; World War, 1914-1918--War work; World War, 1939-1945; World War, 1939-1945--United States; Belgium; United States--Foreign relations; United States--Neutrality; Phonorecords
Biographical Note
1877, July 8 Born, Anamosa, Indiana
1898 B.S., University of Minnesota
1901 M.D., University of Chicago
1918-1919 Physician with Red Cross in France and Belgium
1926-1929 Professor of Obstetrics and Gynecology, University of Minnesota
1929 Professor of Obstetrics and Gynecology, University of Chicago
1930 Chairman, Committee on Prenatal Care, Hoover Conference on Child Health and Protection
1940 Author, Obstetric Medicine, Fetal and Prenatal Death
1940-1942 Member, America First Committee, Chicago Chapter
Container List
- Correspondence, 1918-1919 (Box 1)
- Biographical account of F. L. Adair's medical service in Belgium, 1918
- Reports to the American Red Cross on medical care for children and expectant mothers, 1918
- Red Cross pamphlets
- Medical notes and hospital diagnosis forms
- Newspaper clippings, 1918-1919
- Postcards of Europe, 1918-1919
- Passes and orders
- Mementos, 1918-1919
- Newspaper clippings, February 23, 1892 (about Lincoln's birthday) and May 1888 (about a tribute to Roscoe Conkling)
- America First Committee, 1940-1942 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence
  - Organizational records
  - Campaign materials
  - Printed matter
  - Newspaper clippings
- Miscellany (Box 3)
  - Correspondence
  - Professional papers
  - Genealogy
  - Biographical matter (Box 4)
  - Memorabilia
  - Diplomas and certificates
  - Medals
  - Writings (Box 5)
  - Writings (Box 6)
  - Notes
  - Postcards
  - Address cards
  - Photographs and slides (Box 7-8)
- Diplomas and certificates (On shelf)